<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Jaime Carlos Velez</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Jaime Carlos Velez</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>AboutMe</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/aboutme/aboutme/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//localhost:1313/aboutme/aboutme/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;-jaime-here&#34;&gt;👋 Jaime Here!
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data Analyst&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before anything else&amp;hellip; Yes, I did use my name as a greeting. &lt;em&gt;/Hay.-meh/&lt;/em&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say that I am a professional with a knack for turning data into actionable insights and making operations run like a machine. Currently, I’m a Plant Manager at a small manufacturing business, where I lead a cross-functional team, overseeing logistics, sales, customer service, and ensure smooth operations. From streamlining processes to generating insightful reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before managing that facility, I dived deep into the world of data and people. As a Business Process Delivery Associate at one of the top outsourcing companies in my country, I handled various workloads in membership, claims processing, data entry, and financial operations, ensuring accuracy and compliance at every step. This experience sharpened my analytical skills and taught me the importance of detail-oriented work. Later, as a Recruitment Officer, I discovered I did like connecting with people and collaborating with other recruiters and candidates in the hiring processes even if that was shortlived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a background in Computer Science, I’ve always been drawn to data and technology, leading me to earn certifications in Google Data Analytics, Business Intelligence, and Six Sigma. Whether it’s transcribing audio with precision, creating dashboards in Excel, , I thrive on challenges that blend strategy, analysis, and teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of work, you would maybe find me gaming. I like how gamers really use data-driven decisions. Whether it’s analyzing stats to improve strategies, or which skills works best with what armor and weapons. Have you seen the player in Elden Ring one-shotting bosses? That there is hundreds of rows and columns containing stats, gears, consumables, etc. I love using my analytical mindset with a bit of fun or watch people use it. For me, it’s all about discovering new ways to play and solve problems at the same time. aside from that&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m prolly watching a movies or a series or listening to a audio fiction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by! Feel free to connect with me on LinkedIn or drop a message—I&amp;rsquo;d love to chat!
all the links are in the sidebar&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Coffee Sales Excel Dashboard</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/p/coffee-sales/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//localhost:1313/p/coffee-sales/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="//localhost:1313/p/coffee-sales/cover.JPG" alt="Featured image of post Coffee Sales Excel Dashboard" /&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>food stocks comparisons</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/p/food-stocks/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//localhost:1313/p/food-stocks/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Collect -&amp;gt; Data Ingestion
Clean -&amp;gt; Data Cleaning
Splice &amp;amp; Prepare -&amp;gt; Data Transformation
Visualize -&amp;gt; Dashboarding&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Wordle with Python</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/p/wordle-with-python/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//localhost:1313/p/wordle-with-python/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="//localhost:1313/p/wordle-with-python/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Wordle with Python" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python Wordle is a fun word-guessing game you can play in the terminal. Guess the secret word in a few tries with hints after each guess. Simple, quick, and addictive!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//localhost:1313/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>//localhost:1313/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
